42 chapter 43 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna suul chapter 43 A Friend in
Need The election day came at last; there was no lack of work for Jerry and me.
First came a stout puffy gentleman with a carpet bag; he wanted to go to the
Bishop's Gate station; then we were called by a party who wished to be taken
to the Regent Park; and next we were wanted in the side street where a timid
an ious old lady was waiting to be taken
to the bank; there we had to stop to take
her back again, and just as we had set her down a red-faced gentleman, with a
handful of papers, came running up out of breath, and before Jerry could get down
he had opened the door, popped himself in, and called out, “Bow Street Police Station,
quick!” so off we went with him, and when after another turn or two we came back,
there was no other cab on the stand.
Jerry put on my nose bag for as he said,
“We must eat when we can on such days as these; so munch away, Jack, and make the
best of your time, old boy.” I found I had a good feed of crushed
oats wetted up with a little bran; this would be a treat any day, but very
refreshing then. Jerry was so thoughtful and kind— —what horse would not do his best for such a
master? Then he took out one of pol's meat pies, and standing near me, he began
to eat it. The streets were very full, and the cabs, with the candidates' colors on
them, were dashing about through the crowd as if life and limb were of no
consequence; we saw two people knocked down that day, and one was a
woman. The horses were having a bad time of it, poor things! but the voters inside
thought nothing of that; many of them were half drunk Harring out of the cab
windows if their own party came by. It was the first election I had seen, and I
don't want to be in another, though I have heard things are better
now cherry and I had not eaten many many mouthfuls before a poor young woman,
carrying a heavy child, came along the street. She was looking this way and that
way, and seemed quite bewildered. Presently she made her way up
to Jerry and asked if he could tell her the way to St Thomas's Hospital, and how
far it was to get there. She had come from the country that morning, she said,
in a market cart; she did not know about the election, and was quite a stranger in
London. She had got an order for the hospital for her little boy. The child
was crying with a feeble, pining cry. “Poor little fellow!” she said, “he
suffers a great deal of pain; he is four years old and can't walk any more than a
baby; but the doctor said if I could get him into the hospital he might get well;
pray, sir, how far is it; and which way is it?” “Why Miss said Jerry, “you can't get
there walking through crowds like this!
why, it is three miles away, and that child is
heavy.” “Yes, bless him, he is; but I am
strong, thank God, and if I knew the way I think I should get on somehow; please
tell me the way.” “You can't do it,” said Jerry, “you might
be knocked down and the child be run over. Now look here, just get into this
cab, and I'll drive you safe to the hospital. Don't you see the rain is coming
on?” “No, sir, no; I can't do that, thank you, I
have only just enough money to get back with. Please tell me the
way.” “Look you here Mrs said Jerry, “I've got a wife and dear children at
home, and I know her father's feelings; now get you into that cab, and I'll take
you there for nothing. I'd be ashamed of myself to let a woman and a sick child
run a risk like that.” “Heaven bless you!” said the woman, and burst into
tears. “There, there, cheer up, my dear, I'll soon take you there; come, let me put you
inside.” As Jerry went to open the door two men, with colors in their hats and
button holes ran up calling out, “Cab!” “Engaged,” cried Jerry; but one of the men,
pushing past the woman, sprang into the cab, followed by the other. Jerry looked as stern as a
policeman. “This cab is already engaged, gentlemen, by that
lady.” “Lady!” said one of them; “oh! she can wait; our business is very important,
besides we were in first, it is our right, and we shall stay in.” A droll smile came
over Jerry's face as he shut the door upon them. “All right gentleman pray stay
in as long as it suits you; I can wait while you rest
yourselves.” And turning his back upon them he walked up to the young woman, who
was standing near me. “They'll soon be gone,” he said, laughing; “don't trouble yourself, my
dear.” And they soon were gone, for when they understood Jerry's dodge they got
out, calling him all sorts of bad names and blustering about his number and getting a
summons. After this little stoppage we were soon on our way to the hospital
hpal going as much as possible through by streets Jerry rang the great bell and
helped the young woman out. “Thank you a thousand times,” she said;
“I could never have got here alone.” “You're kindly welcome, and I hope the dear child
will soon be better.” He watched her go in at the door, and gently he said to
himself in as much as he have done it to one of the least of
these.” Then he patted my neck, which was always his way when anything pleased
him. The rain was now coming down fast, and just as we were leaving the hospital
the door opened again, and the porter called out, “Cab!” We stopped, and a lady
came down the steps. Jerry seemed to know her at once; she put back her veil and
said, “Barker! Jeremiah Barker, is it you I'm very glad to find you here; you are
just the friend I want, for it is very difficult to get a cab in this part of
London today I should be proud to serve you, ma'am I'm right glad I happened to be
here. Where may I take you to, ma'am?” “To the Paddington Station, and then if we
are in good time, as I think we shall be,
you shall tell me all about Mary and the children.” We got to the station in good
time, and being under shelter the lady stood a good while talking to Jerry. I
found she had been pol's mistress, and after many inquiries about her she said:
“How do you find the cab work suit you in winter? I know Mary was rather anxious
about you last year.” “Yes, ma'am, she was; I had a bad cough
that followed me quite up into the warm weather, and when I am kept out late she
does worry herself a good deal. You see, ma'am, it is all hours and all weathers,
and that does try a man's constitution; but I'm getting on pretty well, and I
should feel quite lost if I had not horses to look after. I was brought up to
it, and I afraid I should not do so well at anything
else.” “Well, Barker,” she said, “it would be a great pity that you should seriously
risk your health in this work, not only for your own but for Mary's and the
children's sake; there are many places where good drivers or good grooms are
wanted, and if ever you think you ought to give up this cab work let me
know.” Then sending some kind messages to Mary she put something into his hand,
saying, “There is five shillings each for the two children; Mary will know how to
spend it.” Jerry thanked her and seemed much pleased, and turning out of the
station we last reached home, and I, at least, was tired end of chapter